okay third meditation if I could answer
like a mirror then when you stand in
front of a mirror you don't have to ask
the mirror to show you yourself it's
just automatic that's the nature of a
mirror when you put something in front
of a mirror the mirror will show it
automatically you don't have to ask the
mirror please show me myself okay you
just stand in front of the mirror and
it's automatic
okay and the idea here is that the way
of Buddha serves people is automatic
it's like a mirror okay when you provide
the mirror Buddha will be there
okay when you give Buddha a place to
come Buddha will come and Buddha doesn't
think about it it's called some ghee do
puffs and dirt and it's such an
important idea that many monks are
called sentiments
guess it's simple first name was thunder
in Wisconsin so it means subject means
it just shows up automatically ascend it
means automatically okay when you reach
enlightenment you have the power to show
up automatically when someone needs you
so a person in need is like a mirror and
a Buddha will show up there and there's
a beautiful section in the laundry room
we'll get to it's like the moon reflects
in any body of water and it doesn't
matter if it's a Pacific ocean or a lake
or a puddle on the street in Hong Kong
or appear in someone's eye if there's
water surface the moon will shine the
moon will appear in that water
doesn't matter where it is or how big it
is or how small it is Buddha will appear
Buddha will come if you ask okay all
right okay if you ask them they will
come okay
and that's thunder they don't think
about it it just happens okay it's
automatic when someone needs them they
show up okay so when you do the third
meditation goodness without thought I
would like you to will meditate it will
practice it together but I like you to
think about what it would be like to
have that power
okay what if I had that time you know so
I like to think I don't know why I
always see a bus in Guangzhou and a old
lady in Los Angeles and maybe somebody
in Paris and they're all having a bad
day in two different cities around this
world and then Buddha appears to them
you know and I think it's very common
that Buddha will appear as a small dog
for old ladies that's why so many old
ladies have small dogs because Buddha
just appears they need company their
husband died and they feel lonely and
then good over here as a small dog and
they can walk the dog and you know like
that they will appear on a bus to help
an old lady off the bus into the bus or
something like that you know huh they
are doing this stuff now all the times
every moment they are doing this all
over the world they're just towing out
where people need them okay so I think
it'd be nice when we do that meditation
you think about how it would be
have this power okay you want to do it
right now let's do it right now so get
ready to meditate I want to do a
meditation with you at least once before
you do your retreat so that's great
turn off your phone I notice the cell
phone towers are getting closer you
might have to move yeah put on something
to keep yourself warm Jenny
okay good let's go
instead of the train pulling your tummy
just a little bit bring your shoulder
blades together open your chest relax
your fingers
come to your bread try to learn to come
to your breath quickly bring your mind
down into your breath quickly
and try to imagine yourself as you will
be a Buddha
and you will see that Buddha directly
for the first time when you see
emptiness directly right after that
experience in in the few hours following
that experience you will see yourself as
you will be a Buddha taking care of an
entire world so I'd like to look at this
Buddha as a standing on top of the sky
you know so their feet are the bottom of
their feet are facing the verse but they
are standing high above the atmosphere
standing on the atmosphere Venable
jing-mei
asked me what should we call the press
that we have for printing Buddhist books
I said let's call it standing on the sky
press you so you're standing and you are
looking down at your world that you're
in charge of it's your responsibility as
a Buddha to focus on this particular
world
and help the beings in this world so you
feel sort of like a mom watching her
child in a crib or something this is
your world to help take care of it and
I'd like you to imagine this Buddha is
like a moon shining full moon and then
down there on the surface of this earth
our bodies of water oceans lakes puddles
teardrops
and your life of your moon shines in
each one as soon as the water faces you
you appear in the water like a mirror
like stepping in front of a mirror but
those bodies of water are people who
need something so I'd like you to
imagine the Americas the South in North
America and choose a city that you comes
to mind and imagine someone in that city
who needs help today and you decide what
kind of help it could be they just lost
their boyfriend or girlfriend or husband
or wife or they just found out the
device sink to have serious disease they
just lost their job they don't know what
to do you choose a city and you choose a
an imaginary person or someone you know
in the Americas
who had the problem
and then imagine that you step in front
of that mirror and you become someone or
something that could help them maybe is
a dear friend or a child who comforts
them or a teacher or a little dog you
choose something and step in front of
the mirror of the person who needs you
getting badges you're helping them in a
place in the Americas
then stay in that body of the friend or
the dog in the Americas and then move
your mind to Europe look down on Europe
Western or Eastern Europe and choose a
city
and then decide think of a person who
might need you
let's do the whole strip like Middle
East Africa Europe
and think of someone who needs something
to the city create a imaginary person or
think of a person you know about say in
Syria or something and come to them as
as a friend
protector someone to love reflect in
that mirror in that puddle of water of a
person who needs you
but don't let go the the one in America
in the Americas keep that one going and
create a second
now move your mind to Asia no I think
that
and do the same thing think of any city
to the city ho Chi Minh Singapore
Jakarta Gong Cheol Shanghai Beijing you
choose
imagine a person there who had some
problem don't let go of the first two
bodies you took in the Americas and in
the strip of Europe and Middle East
Africa hold those two and now choose a
city in Asia
imagine someone in trouble needs help or
to someone you know and step in front of
that mirror of a person in need and
appear suddenly in their life as a
friend or a teacher or maybe as their
child someone they can love
and enter this third body at the same
time as you keep the other tooth
and keep those three bodies going
helping three different people and bring
your mind back to yourself standing on
the sky those three bodies are still
living helping people but bring your
attention back to yourself as the
Buddha's standing in the sky
and then three long exhales to come back
and then slowly open your eyes take a
good stretch
[Music]